Carmen Ng

Front-end Web Developer

An adaptable and motivated individual with a strong understanding of visual communications currently working as a Senior Frontend Developer at Launch Tabletop. Over 7 years of web development experience has allowed me to develop strong analytical and problem solving skills. I am eager to continue learning new skills and gain more experience in various areas and languages as I am always striving for self improvement, both professionally and personally.

carmenng.media@gmail.com

Hong Kong

in linkedin.com/in/carng

Available via Email

nightlightvisuals.com

github.com/CarNg

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Developer

Launch Tabletop 🗷

03/2022 - Present

- Develop and maintain LTT's website.
- Work with UX team to improve UX for LTT app modules.
- R&D for upcoming features and services for LTT app modules.

Senior Software Engineer

OpenRice 🗷

09/2019 - 03/2022

- Develop & maintain OpenRice.com and Biz.OpenRice.com
- Supervise & manage team members' from overseas offices to ensure high quality, timely delivery of tasks
- Collaborate with other teams, such as Product Design, UI Design, QA and Backend Team, for regular builds with new features

Solutions Developer

PCCW Solutions 2

04/2017 - 09/2019

- Redesign & develop the frontend (JSP, JavaScript, jQuery) for clients' existing ERP systems.
- Work directly with BAs to design and develop better UX.
- API connection to existing Oracle E-Business ERP (Java).

Full Stack Developer

RT-Technology Ideas Holding Ltd.

04/2016 - 03/2017

RT-Technology is behind BabyPOS POS system. They also provide services in web design & development and SEO optimisation.

- Develop & maintain the web platform for BabyPOS.
- Connect BabyPOS API to clients' online shops.
- Design & develop clients' websites and online shops.

EDUCATION

MSc in Creative Digital Media

Technological University Dublin (previously DIT)

00/2013 - 02/2015

First Class Honours

BA (Hons) Journalism and Visual Media

Griffith College Dublin

09/2009 - 07/2012

First Class Honours

SKILLS

React Next.js

Node.js Vue.js

Less Shopify

Skill .NET

Tailwind

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Night Light Visuals (2015 - Present)

 Night Light Visuals is my personal branding and portfolio site for previous and current projects. The website is built using Next.js and tailwind.

This Time Around (02/2014 - 02/2015)

 'This Time Around' is an interactive fiction/exploration game developed as a MSc final project. My responsibilities included game design (mechanics & aesthetics), narrative creation, programming using C# in Unity3D, sound design, QA, testing with users and analysing results, marketing the game, write a full report detailing the process of game development from research to final product.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Best Game Script Nominee (06/2018)

Nominated for a Writers' Guild of Ireland ZeBBie Award in Best Game Script as a co-writer of Simteractive's Eden Isle: Resort Paradise

LANGUAGES

English
Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Cantonese

Professional Working Proficiency